<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><id>https://giacomocaironi.github.io</id><title>Giacomo Caironi</title><updated>2020-05-21T21:17:13.806791+00:00</updated><link href="https://giacomocaironi.github.io"/><link href="https://giacomocaironi.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/><generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="0.9.0">python-feedgen</generator><entry><id>https://giacomocaironi.github.io/blog/posts/why-I-built-kart/</id><title>Why I built Kart</title><updated>2020-05-14T12:00:00+00:00</updated><content>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;A while ago I started studying python web frameworks and I settled with Flask, a very flexible micro-framework. I preferred it over Django because I could have much over control over the way the site was built. However after a while my very simple test site became really intricate, because I needed a new package to have a feature that are required my modern sites. I build a simple site aggregator with Flask, but in the end I wasn't satisfied by the result. Anyway I then tried to build a blog with Flask; however I realized that it was difficult to create a page that could be edited using a WYSIWYG (What you see is what you get) editor. Later I discovered some packages that could render Markdown on the fly in the browser, which is somewhat what I would have liked, but anyway I was committed to something I discovered in that period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first learned about static site generators when I discovered Github Pages. It seemed a fantastic thing, a place where I could host my site for fre&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link href="https://giacomocaironi.github.io/blog/posts/why-I-built-kart/" rel="alternate"/></entry><entry><id>https://giacomocaironi.github.io/projects/kart/</id><title>Kart</title><updated>2020-03-21T12:00:00+00:00</updated><content>A very flexible static site generator written in python</content><link href="https://giacomocaironi.github.io/projects/kart/" rel="alternate"/></entry><entry><id>https://giacomocaironi.github.io/projects/flask-quickstart/</id><title>Flask Quickstart</title><updated>2019-06-01T12:00:00+00:00</updated><content>Skeleton for a flask website with built-in user authentication and admin interface</content><link href="https://giacomocaironi.github.io/projects/flask-quickstart/" rel="alternate"/></entry></feed>